earthtrekkers.com 2019-06-21

# Privacy Policy | Earth Trekkers

### Privacy Policy

Your privacy is important to Earth Trekkers. This privacy statement provides information about the personal information that we collect and the ways in which we use that personal information. By visiting our website, you are accepting the practices described in this Privacy Policy.

This Privacy Policy forms part of our [Terms and Conditions of Use](https://www.earthtrekkers.com/terms-of-use/) document.

#### Collection of your Information

**Information You Voluntarily Submit:  ** We collect your information when you voluntarily enter it into our website. This can include signing up for our newsletter, commenting on a post, or otherwise entering information on our website. ** **

**Automatically-Collected Information** : We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access this website. For example, when you use this website, we will log your IP address, operating system type, browser type, pages you viewed, and the time when you accessed the Website. We may also collect information about actions you take while using this website, such as links clicked.

#### Use of Your Information

We use your information when answering comments on posts, sending out emails or our newsletter, for maintaining this website, to track advertising, and to protect against unauthorized activity.

We will not use or disclose information that could be used to identify an individual member in any circumstances except to ensure the proper functioning of our business and the website, to communicate promotional offers and special events to you, to allow our trusted third parties, including our advertising partners, to communicate promotional and special offers to you, and where the law requires us to do so.

#### Securing Your Information

Please note that no information transmitted over the internet can be guaranteed to be completely secure. However, we will protect your personal information as best as possible but we cannot guarantee the security of any information that you transmit to us, or receive from us. The transmission and exchange of information is carried out at your own risk.

#### Links to Third Party Websites

This website contains content with links to third party websites. We are not responsible for the privacy policies of these websites. We have no liability for the content and information on these third party websites.

The Website currently uses the following third-party service providers:

Google Analytics: This service tracks Website usage and provides information such as referring websites and user actions on the Website. Google Analytics may capture your IP address, but no other personal information is captured by Google Analytics.

Mediavine: Mediavine is used to manage our display advertisements. To provide personalized advertising options, Mediavine may track your IP address or location. This information is not stored on the Website.

Mailchimp:  Mailchimp is used for delivery of email updates and newsletters. We store your name and email address for purposes of delivering such communications.  Please refer to Mailchimp’s privacy policy for further information.

#### Use of Cookies

Like most websites, we use cookies. Cookies are small pieces of information that are stored on your computer. They are designed to record your browsing history, log in information, and your web surfing history. Personal information is not collected by cookies, however, if you previously provided personal information then cookies may be linked to this information.

In some cases, we use third-party advertising companies to show you ads when you visit our website. These companies may use your stored cookies to provide you advertisements about goods and services that are of an interest to you.

You can disable the use of cookies by changing the setting in your web browser.

#### External Links

We often use external links to provide you with additional information. We accept no responsibility for the content of this links and they are provided as an additional tool to help you in your travel planning.

#### Newsletter

On the Website, you may subscribe to our newsletter, which may be used for advertising purposes. All newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns. Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click. Also, this allows the Website to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of the user.

Any email information submitted for our newsletter will never be passed on to any other parties. You can unsubscribe at any time.

#### Affiliate Marketing

We engage in affiliate marketing, which is done by embedding a tracking link into this website. If you click on one of these affiliate links, a cookie is placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commission.

Earth Trekkers participates in the Amazon Services LLC Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for us to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Amazon.com. As part of our participation in this program, we post customized links, provided by Amazon, to track referrals to their website. This program uses cookies to track visits for the purpose of assigning commission to these sales.

Earth Trekkers also participates in the Booking.com Associates Program, an affiliate advertising program designed to provide a means for us to earn advertising fees by advertising and linking to Booking.com. As part of our participation in this program, we post customized links, provided by Booking.com, to track referrals to their website. This program uses cookies to track visits for the purpose of assigning commission to these sales.

#### Rights Related to Your Personal Information

Opt-Out: You can opt-out of future newsletters by using the unsubscribe link in the newsletter. You can also notify us at info@earthtrekkers.com to be removed from our mailing list.

Access: You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to info@earthtrekkers.com

Amend: You may contact us at info@earthtrekkers.com to amend or update your personal information.

Forget: In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to info@earthtrekkers.com.

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for recordkeeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

#### Sensitive Personal Information

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the Website. This includes your social security number, information regarding race or ethnic origin, political opinions, religious beliefs, health information, criminal background, or trade union memberships. If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

#### Terms and Conditions

By using this site you do so at your own free will. You agree to use the information on this website for information purposes only and at your own risk. In no case will we be liable for any damage or loss due to using this website.

To read more about our terms and conditions, [click here.](https://www.earthtrekkers.com/terms-of-use/)

#### Contact Us

If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, contact us at info@earthtrekkers.com.

_Last Updated February 1, 2019_
